Okay. Hi, [cough] thanks [clears throat]
for signing up for this crazy
experiment. Um, we are being uh I I I
think a lot of us are interested in
building software that people want to
pay money for, but also
uh don't really know the extent to which
uh they can build. And I think a time
scope thing like this exercise or this
game or this competition would be really
interesting. and we are a real customer.
Um, the reason I'm not being public is
to honestly just preserve their um their
privacy. Uh, but I think this will be a
fun exercise and uh, genuinely we are
looking at paying $40,000 for this
software which uh, I'll show you. Um,
you can go to sessionboard.com.
Uh, uh, this is the the rough spec which
you which I'm going to send to you guys
uh, of what we are actually using. So it
is not all the features that we're
looking to clone. Um we want the sort of
program submission you know I run a
conference and we uh get a lot of
submissions for uh for speakers and uh
you know people want to apply and we
have to evaluate them and put them on
the schedule and communicate them and
make them show up and all these things.
So session board is a type of software
in the industry uh which people pay
anywhere between $500 to $200,000 uh a
year to or you know potentially per
event uh to do these things. Um session
board seems very comprehensive. Uh there
are other competitor platforms like
session eyes uh they only do the program
but session board also does CRM also
does marketing also does CMS uh which
delivers content to your thing. So you
can also check this yourself. Um and
also you see uh what's what's nice here
is also you get to see a lot of
screenshots. You cannot do a self um
guided tour. You have to request a demo
uh which is part of the enterprise sales
tactics I don't really want. You can see
all the session boards competitors here.
Uh I think the main message is we are
probably only going to use the program
side of these things and we're probably
not really using the marketing side, not
really using uh the CRM side. Um but you
know, I'll I'll clone as much of of it
as you want uh for your exercise. Um
we're just going to pay attention to the
program side. Um
the the [clears throat] main idea um the
thing that you should set up with it
should look roughly like this. Um you
should probably have some settings where
you can set up the event details. Some
basic stuff here. Um I assume that you
can pause if you want uh to manage uh
this kind of thing. Uh all all good,
right? Um, and we'll we'll give you a
walk through if you want, but uh it
doesn't really matter as long as you
fulfill the uh the main core
um functionality that we describe in the
Google doc. Okay. Um so let's talk about
the Google doc.
Um we're looking at the program. Um and
here this is like a little dashboard
thing. Uh the main thing that the main
uh life cycle is that you have
submissions um uh which can either be
abstracts or uh videos which are sort of
applications to speak and sessions which
are people who are pretty much
guaranteed to speak uh let's say because
they're a sponsor
um uh and you can sort of set up some
kind of abstract session here. Um so I
have already set up um this kinds this
this series of abstracts. So, let me
just kind of part of this I also don't
love is that it's kind of slow.
[clears throat] Um, here you can enter
in manually or you can also um look for
the submission functionality. Uh, which
I can't really tell where it is. Let me
just
part this is this slowness is part of
why uh I think you guys can probably do
a better job than um
than session board.
Um
yeah, I don't know where this the sort
of form thing is. Let me just Oh yeah,
let's copy the form here. So uh in order
to create an abstract uh some
application page you create a form that
looks like this. Um you [clears throat]
want you want abstracts or you want
sessions you can choose down down here.
Uh you have a welcome screen blah blah
blah all the sort of messaging and
customization. Uh let's just go ahead
and select all these things. So you have
like a form builder is what you're being
asked to build here. This is just a very
fancy form builder. That's all it is. Um
you have some limits in terms of the
number of speakers and sponsors uh
speakers and biography and all these
things. Um all of which uh has very
standard validation rules and all these
things. Um
and looks like it doesn't even have full
validation. Very nice. Okay, great.
[clears throat] Um we don't really care
about payment, so you can skip this one
if you're cloning it. Um and then you
have a close date. Let's just call it, I
don't know, September 15th. Doesn't
matter. You can send a reminder email.
Set a submission limit. Um, multiple
draft submissions. Thank you email. Uh,
multi- language. We only care about
English. Um, you should be able to enter
in admins. Um, this one also optional,
you know, uh, just show us the the rough
format. Again, the higher fidelity, the
more usefulness. You are allowed to use
your own judgment as to what this is.
So, we created a form here, uh, form
three, and let's just go and see it
publicly. So, this is this would be the
public link. Um, I'm going to show you
how in incognito we can access this. Um,
and you can submit that form. Um, so
this is the uh, it looks like it's
asking me to to use a password. Uh, I
probably have a password stored, so good
enough. Fill in some blanks. It has some
required fields. Um,
and let's see if uh we can get a quick
submission down here. Excellent.
Excellent. Okay.
Okay. Excellent. Submit.
Um, that was stupid. Obviously, I should
not have a minimum of two speakers.
That's not something that we do. Uh, so
now once you have a login, you can
actually see um your login with the your
speakers and your your tasks. Uh, and
this is this is an important part of it
whether or not you have been accepted or
not. Um, I think that's that's a that's
a key part as well as once you've been
accepted, what tasks do you have to
complete?
That also is kind of optional, but it is
it is very very handy for for people
using this. Um, [snorts] so, oh my god,
this is so slow. Okay. Um, you can see
the the session we just submitted down
here with the two speakers. Uh, as well
as you being able to update your own
biography. Uh, this is a very important
part of the the overall submissions and
obviously being able to send email is
great. Okay, so [clears throat] that is
the bulk of it. Um I think there will be
others. So for example if we go over to
evaluations uh we can create evaluation
plans on the admin side on the uh
conference committee side and we can
assign sessions to be evaluated by
conference committees. So here we can
say all right this team is evaluating uh
whatever numbers of submissions
and uh as a submitter as a as an
evaluator I can um look at look through
all these all these things uh so I think
that's really helpful um once things
have been evaluated accepted and and
information is put out there then we can
um add these um add this add the
accepted sessions in here for the agenda
on putting out publicly uh as well as
obviously um showing them or embedding
them in uh some external environment uh
where you can get the code for example.
Um and here it's roughly how it should
look. Um it's a very standard sort of uh
event display with uh all every
everything all linked uh and what have
you. So that [cough and clears throat]
is the rough idea. Um there's a lot in
here that I'm I'm skimming over uh that
I think we'll have to scope out what the
requirements are. I think there's a lot
uh in in this video itself that can get
you started. I think as long as you
roughly get the idea that we that we
have uh in here uh with this basis you
can also use the session board website
where you can say you can look at the
individual screens. Um you don't it's
not about the fidelity to session board.
It's about filling the job to be done uh
that that fits it. I don't care about
the AI workflow thing. I just care that
uh we have an accepted industry standard
tool that we have open source and we can
clone it in a weekend. Um I think it is
very doable if you're focused on on it.
Um and I think having all these public
uh bullet points gives you some idea of
what that can be. I will be available to
you in the Discord um in order to answer
any questions and probably record a more
professional demo of this.